Mayank Pant

mayankpant317@gmail.com +91 9536867801 Bommanahalli, Bangalore-560068, Karnataka. **DoB:** 31st July 1993

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Seeking a place in a team of passionate and enthusiastic individuals, who really strive to solve the problem.

EXPERIENCE

ShopTrade, Bangalore

Frontend Developer (ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap(v4), jQuery, Liquid Templating Language (Shopify)) (May,2019 - July,2020)

3D Usher, Bangalore

Frontend Developer (January,2019 - April, 2019)

StarApps, Delhi

Frontend Developer Oct 2016 - May 2017

Souq.com (Amazon.ae), Bangalore — *Internship*

Souq.com (now Amazon.ae) is the largest ecommerce site in the Arab world. Now acquired by Amazon.com for \$800 mn. June - July (2015)

SKILLS

ReactJS, JAVASCRIPT (ES6), jQuery, SASS, Bootstrap(v4), HTML5, CSS3, Git

ABOUT

Creation of interactive one page web application using Javascript.

Good understanding of JSON, Ajax and Responsiveness.

React knowledge including Hooks.

Sass, Bootstrap(v4) and git are few of my skills.

Overall good knowledge of web protocols and how information flows between frontend, backend and Rest APIs.

Learning about user experience everyday.

EDUCATION

College Of Engineering Roorkee, Roorkee — B.Tech

2012 - 2016 Computer Science & Technology

LANGUAGE FLUENCY: Hindi, English

Personal Project Links:

To Do List: (July, 2020 - Aug, 2020)

We often mismanage our tasks, so we need a method to prioritize them accordingly. To-Do List resolves this problem. You can check the progress of the tasks that you are working on and you can change status once it's completed.

TECH STACK: Javascript, HTML, SCSS, Firebase, React, Axios,

React-Router-dom

https://my-task-tracker.netlify.app/

Star Wars Characters: (Sept, 2020 - Present)

The page contains a complete detailed description of star wars characters.

You can search characters, sort them accordingly and can get a complete detailed information by visiting a character's page.

TECH STACK: React, Axios, React Router, Star Wars API(swapi), React Font Awesome

https://characters-starwars.netlify.app/

Furniture Cart: (Sept, 2020 - Present)

Vanilla JS single page e-commerce application, where products can be added or remove from cart dynamically.

on page reload cart maintain product availability in cart as product are being added with the help of local Storage.

TECH STACK: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Netlify

https://furniture-js.netlify.app/

Company Project Links:

Elevatione: (Dec, 2019 - present)

A Shopify Plus e-Commerce site for leading international Boutique experience brand, the store is located in cities like New York, Hong Kong, London etc. Following is a link for the live e-commerce site

https://www.elevatione.com/

AerocareDirect : (Oct, 2019 - present)

A Shopify e-Commerce site to provide quality service and care to its patients across all states in USA, the shopify store generates a monthly revenue of \$100k+. Following is a link for the live e-commerce site

https://www.aerocaredirect.com/